<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0/blog/pastors" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">

<channel>

<title>The Journey's Blog</title>

<link>http://journeyon.net/blog/pastors</link>

<description>Love God. Connect People. Transform the World.</description>

<language>en</language>

<item>
<title>Impossible to Please</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7685</link>
<description> <![CDATA[

		Sometimes God is impossible to please.

		&amp;ldquo;Without faith it is impossible to please [God],&amp;rdquo; it says in Hebrews. But pleasing God is obviously the goal of worship. So what does living a life of worship through faith look like?

		Hebrews 11, the great faith chapter, opens by saying that everyone in the Old Testament that pleased God did it through trusting in Jesus. They hoped for a promised Savior and lived in light of that promise. The author tells us they:


			Lived in reverent fear (vs. 7)

			Obeyed God&amp;rsquo;s call (vs. 8 )

			Trusted that God is faithful to His promises (vs. 11)

			Generously and sacrificially offered up their greatest earthly treasures (vs. 4 &amp;amp; 17)

			Chose suffering and mistreatment over comfortable living (vs. 25 &amp;amp; 36-38)

			Treasured Christ over wealth and earthly treasures (vs. 26)

			Weren&amp;rsquo;t afraid (vs. 27)

			Enforced justice (vs. 33)


		The list goes on. For these believers, trust and hope led to obedience and sacrifice. Because they knew God would keep His promises, their whole lives were oriented toward pleasing him. And because they lived by faith, they were able to.

		The Old Testament heroes cited in Hebrews 11 hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen the fulfillment of those promises, and yet still lived by faith. How much more should we trust God, having already received the promised Redeemer?

		Consider all that he has done for us:


			He left his throne in heaven to be born as a helpless baby

			Grew up as a perfectly innocent man

			Fulfilled all Old Testament prophecies concerning the Messiah

			Died to satisfy the wrath of God against us because of our sin

			Was raised from the dead

			Sent his Holy Spirit as an Encourager, Helper and deposit to assure us of His promise

			Always intercedes for us before the Father

			Is coming soon to restore all things


		Given all that we have seen, you might think we could teach the Old Testament heroes a thing or two.

		But we still trust in ourselves, our talents, our riches, and our goals. We have fooled ourselves into thinking those please Him. We believe that we can live a life centered on ourselves, come to church to sing and take communion, and those will please Him.

		But true worship does not happen apart from faith. Let&amp;rsquo;s ask God to help us in our weakness and &amp;ldquo;increase our faith!&amp;rdquo; so that we can earnestly desire and pursue Him in a way that truly does please Him.

		Follow Stephen on Twitter, and The Journey on Twitter and Facebook.
]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>On the Sabbath</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7645</link>
<description> <![CDATA[Last week&amp;#39;s staff meeting was particularly resourceful and has begun a dialogue I hope will continue in the Journey staff. &amp;nbsp;We talked about the commandment of the Sabbath. &amp;nbsp;In my leadership notes, I would put this under &amp;quot;leading self&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;personal discipline.&amp;quot; &amp;nbsp;First, Pastor Joel noted that while we think about outer disciplines it&amp;rsquo;s extremely important to think about the inner disciplines. &amp;nbsp;
	We need to realize &amp;ldquo;God is God and we are not,&amp;rdquo; Joel said. &amp;nbsp;He went further to add that each of us is not responsible for &amp;ldquo;making the world around us,&amp;rdquo; or our church, or even our departments and ministries. &amp;nbsp;I noted to myself that when I take a Sabbath I come into contact with this reality in a way I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t otherwise because I&amp;rsquo;ve given up control (even if just for an hour or a day). &amp;nbsp;Underneath this is a trust issue for me, resting in two things: &amp;nbsp;1. I have to trust that my identity is not tied to my work. &amp;nbsp;2. I have to trust that God is really in control, and if I&amp;#39;m not involved for a little bit, things will still go on without me. &amp;nbsp;
	Pastor Joel also said we need to realize and admit we are enslaved to our work. &amp;nbsp;Joel taught us that the key to freedom is within our reach&amp;mdash;it&amp;rsquo;s a Sabbath.&amp;nbsp; 
	In my own notes, I wrote down two words: &amp;nbsp;Identity and Guilt. &amp;nbsp;I already spoke about how identity and trust are an issue. &amp;nbsp;The guilt thing is akin to feeling bad for taking time off work. &amp;nbsp;I am wrestling through exactly why that is so. &amp;nbsp;Identity is again an issue there. &amp;nbsp;Whose standard do I feel I&amp;#39;m not meeting in a way that guilt is the product?
	I also see that while Sabbath is a separate idea from work, because we are in ministry the two can be tough to separate, particularly when I love my work, work with my friends, and spend time with God as a part of my job. &amp;nbsp;As our staff talked with one another, it was easy to see the correlation between how we think about work and how we think about rest. &amp;nbsp;In fact, it was almost impossible for us to talk about one without talking about the other. &amp;nbsp;If you have thoughts on Sabbath, I&amp;#39;d love to hear them. &amp;nbsp;Here are a couple books that have helped me think about it. They are in no way the total gospel on Sabbath, but like any book, it&amp;#39;s a great place to start thinking and processing along with God&amp;#39;s word.
	The Sabbath by Abraham Joshua Heschel
	The Way of the Heart by Henri Nouwen]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>How He Loves</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7640</link>
<description> <![CDATA[
	A couple of years back, this song &amp;ldquo;How He Loves&amp;rdquo; surfaced. Written by John Mark McMillan, I actually heard a version from Eddie Kirkland first. I was immediately in love with it. The poetry and imagery were strong and beautiful. The message was inspiring. As a guy who really struggles to believe how much God loves me, it was very refreshing for me to listen to. However, then I began to hear it being used all over in corporate worship settings and I was frankly very concerned.

	I always strive to maintain a Christ-centered, gospel-centered approach to my worship leadership. If the glory of Christ and the cross are not the focus of our songs and the thrust of everything we are presenting in a corporate worship gathering, it&amp;rsquo;s all pointless. As a result, it&amp;rsquo;s been incredibly easy for me to gravitate toward the truth that Jesus died for His glory, but unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s often been at the expense of believing it was out of His love for us as well. I regrettably have almost fostered a distaste for singing about God&amp;rsquo;s love for us in a corporate worship setting. I want to focus on His glory, sovereignty, power and other manly type topics.

	But no matter how much I struggle to exalt these incredible attributes of God, the fact of this strong biblical truth remains: that He demonstrated His love for us in this: that while we were still sinners, Christ died for us. His love for His creation was indeed quite a motivator for His crusade to conquer sin, even become sin on our behalf, so that He might impute His righteousness to us. We cannot leave this out of the story we present in worship in our churches; it MUST inform the way we worship and plan for leading worship.

	Bryan Chapell, in his book, &amp;ldquo;Christ-Centered Worship&amp;rdquo; says,

	&amp;ldquo;Worship is not only for God&amp;rsquo;s glory, and it is not only for our good. In order for the gospel to be good news for God&amp;rsquo;s people it must have both goals, and worship that is reflective of the gospel must also have both goals&amp;hellip; Making God&amp;rsquo;s glory the exclusive goal of worship sounds very reverent, but actually fails to respect Scripture&amp;rsquo;s own gospel priorities.&amp;rdquo;

	He goes on to say,

	&amp;ldquo;The vertical, heaven directed aspects of worship do not require us to ignore human concerns. In fact, praising God without acknowledging His love for His people would make our worship incomplete&amp;hellip; In order for our worship to minister God&amp;rsquo;s goodness to His people, we must have a means to reflect His love in our liturgy.&amp;rdquo;

	God has done a complete 180 in my heart toward &amp;ldquo;How He Loves.&amp;rdquo; I used to question its appropriateness in a congregational worship setting, but now I question how one can corporately worship without addressing the great love with which He has loved us. One of the most man-centered things we could do is ignore the very love God gave His son to display. He glories in His own love enough to call Himself Love. If we ignore that, we ignore a large portion of who God chooses to identify Himself as.

	However, keeping a Christ-centered view of God&amp;rsquo;s love in singing this song must always and unwaveringly be our goal. Our Savior is who we are singing to, and who our affections are being directed at. He is the subject of the song. It is His love&amp;hellip; We must not make the mistake of exalting ourselves as the subjects of the song, as could potentially be our tendency in any type of worship. That&amp;rsquo;s why a good worship leader will shepherd people away from that idolatry by keeping the focus on Christ&amp;rsquo;s character and work.

	At this juncture, I must point out that the song does not ever specifically mention Christ, or the cross. This does not make it unusable&amp;hellip; many songs never make mention specifically of those things. It does, however, incline the worship leader to insert a rubric of some sort as an introduction to the song, pointing out that the ultimate sacrifice and infinite cost Christ paid on the cross was the full demonstration of His love for us.

	Christ is absolutely everything! He is the subject of the song, and object of our affection and His great love with which He has loved us ought to spur our hearts toward a lively worship and affection for Him because of who He is and all He has done.

	I will be planning and using &amp;ldquo;How He Loves&amp;rdquo; in my worship sets.]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>Acts 29 Midwest Quarterly</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7619</link>
<description> <![CDATA[
	Author, strategic thinker and movement leader, Alan Hirsch will be speaking at our next Acts29 Midwest Region Quarterly, Tuesday, August 17, 2010. Alan brings a wealth of insight and experience as a global leader and movement shaper calling the Church back to its roots as a Community on Mission.


	 Register here.

	Alan is the founding Director of Forge Mission Training Network. He is the co-founder of shapevine.com, a ministry of Christianity Today International and an international forum for engaging with world transforming ideas. Currently, he leads an innovative learning program called Future Travelers, helping numerous mega-churches become missional movements.&amp;nbsp;He has also been part of the leadership team of Christian Associates, a missional church-planting agency with focus on Western Europe.

	

	Known for his innovative approach to mission, Alan is a teacher and key mission strategist for churches across the western world. His popular book The Shaping of Things to Come (with Michael Frost) is widely considered to be a seminal text on mission. Alan&amp;#39;s recent book, The Forgotten Ways, has quickly become a key reference for missional thinking, particularly as it relates to missional movements. His book ReJesus is a radical restatement about the role that Jesus plays in defining Christian movements. Untamed, his most recent book (with his wife Debra) is about missional discipleship for a missional church.

	

	His experience in leadership includes leading a local church movement, among the marginalized, developing training systems for innovative missional leadership, as well as heading up the Mission and Revitalization work of his denomination. Alan is and adjunct professor at Fuller Seminary, George Fox Evangelical Seminary, and Wheaton, among others, and lectures frequently throughout Australia, Europe, and the U.S.

	Event Details

	When: Tuesday, August 17

	Time: 10 AM &amp;ndash; 2 PM (registration opens at 9 AM)

	Where: The Journey, Tower Grove Campus Sanctuary

	Cost: FREE, including lunch&amp;nbsp;

	

	Session 1: Empowering and Releasing Your Church for Mission

	Lunch Discussion: Pastor Darrin Patrick on The Journey&amp;rsquo;s move to Missional Community

	Session 2: Addressing the Clergy&amp;mdash;Laity Divide

	

	Register here.

	

	Sponsorships:&amp;nbsp;If you&amp;rsquo;d like information on becoming a sponsor, please email Katie at kwachter@journeyon.net]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>Making Memorization Possible</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7591</link>
<description> <![CDATA[
	When I was a kid, I wanted to be just like Michael Jordan. &amp;nbsp;I didn&amp;rsquo;t need Nike to tell me to &amp;ldquo;be like Mike.&amp;rdquo;


	I saw Air Jordan on TV, recognized he was the best, and went out to dominate my invisible opponents and get my &amp;quot;dunk on&amp;quot; with my 7-foot goal, wagging tongue and all.
	For you, it may not have been Mike, but you had somebody that you wanted to be like. And you and I never really grow out of that kind of wonder, which is why we admire people who push the boundaries of what we think is possible. &amp;nbsp;
	What does this have to do with memorizing Scripture? &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s sometimes hard for us to know what&amp;rsquo;s possible when it comes to memorizing the word. &amp;nbsp;There aren&amp;rsquo;t many people running around who have devoted themselves to keeping Scripture in their hearts, and so it&amp;rsquo;s hard to find people to imitate.
	Here are two people, though, that are worth imitating. 
	First, watch Ryan Ferguson recite Psalm 22. Then read an interview with Ryan.
	Second, Ben Patterson is a master memorizer. &amp;nbsp;In this interview, Ben discusses how he got into memorizing Scripture, his strategy for it, and the benefits that come with Scripture memorization.&amp;nbsp; The appropriate section starts at 24:15 (HT: Justin Taylor). 
	You may never be Ben Patterson or Ryan Ferguson, and I&amp;#39;m definitely not Michael Jordan. &amp;nbsp;But we can improve our practice by learning from these experts.&amp;nbsp; 
	And when it comes to hiding God&amp;rsquo;s word in our hearts, that is a goal worth seeking.]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>Summer Brown Bag Lunch Series</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7582</link>
<description> <![CDATA[
	Looking for a change of pace this summer.&amp;nbsp; Brown Bag it with us!


	RSVP here.

	One opportunity to take advantage of this change-in-pace is the Summer Brown Bag Lunch Series. This series continues on August 12 with Rev. Scott Sauls, Upper West Side Lead Pastor at Redeemer Presbyterian Church in New York City.

	You are invited to come, bring your lunch, and interact with gospel truth, the Journey staff, and excellent teaching.

	If you would like childcare, please sign up here before August 9.]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>Tools for Memorizing Scripture</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7572</link>
<description> <![CDATA[
	Technology is a double-edged sword.

	On the one hand, it is a fantastic tool that helps communities preserve content over long periods of time. &amp;nbsp;We don&amp;rsquo;t tend to think of books as technology, but they are, and they preserve ideas so individuals don&amp;rsquo;t have to.
	On the other hand, being too dependent on technology can make memorizing Scripture seem archaic and unimportant. &amp;nbsp;If we can simply access a verse from your favorite Bible app on your iPhone why memorize Scripture?

	It&amp;rsquo;s a good question, and one that we have answered before. &amp;nbsp;But while technology can make memorizing seem less important, it can also help us memorize. &amp;nbsp;
	Consider the following three tools:

	1) Memorize Now  takes a bit of text from a verse and drops the words away so that we can replace them mentally. &amp;nbsp;It&amp;rsquo;s almost like reverse Hangman, the game we used to play during spelling lessons.

	2) Verse Card Maker is for those who want to implement the handy system of notecards, but who (like me) have terrible handwriting. &amp;nbsp;It spits out a set of cards to print verses easily.
	3) Sometimes hearing Scripture read out loud can change our experience of it, and embed it more deeply into our minds. &amp;nbsp;While there are a number of audiorecordings of the Bible available, the ESV allows you to hear any passage of the Bible you want. &amp;nbsp;For instance, check out this week&amp;#39;s memory verse, 2 Corinthians 5:21.
	Of course, no technology will substitute for hard work. &amp;nbsp;Memorizing the Bible isn&amp;rsquo;t easy, but its benefits are immeasurable--and the more you do it, the easier it gets.
	If you have any other tips and tools, feel free to let us know at The Journey&amp;#39;s Facebook Page or on The City.]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>How To Memorize Scripture: Repetition &amp; Review</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7552</link>
<description> <![CDATA[
	Scripture memorization doesn&amp;#39;t just happen. It&amp;#39;s a discipline.&amp;nbsp; It&amp;#39;s hard. It takes commitment.


	We have to devote ourselves to it if we want to benefit from it. And it is easier for some than others. As such, most of us have given up (or never tried at all). My hope with this post is to equip us with some practical methods for memorizing passages of Scripture. Coming to our aid once again is Pastor John Piper, who provides some excellent guidelines based on personal experience. Below is an excerpt from one of Piper&amp;#39;s articles on ways to memorize Scripture.&amp;nbsp; You can view the full article by clicking here.


		Set aside 5-10 minutes everyday.

		Take your first verse, read it ten times, and then close your eyes or shut your Bible and say it ten times. And that&amp;#39;s the end for that day.

		Come back the next day. You open your Bible up, and you say that verse again 5 or 10 times. If it&amp;#39;s easy, just 5 times. And then you do the same thing with the next verse. And then you do them both together. And then you shut your Bible and you leave. Basically, the answer is: repetition and review. Repetition and review.

		If I pick a verse or a couple of verses or a paragraph, I&amp;#39;ll put it on a piece of paper and I&amp;#39;ll carry it around in my shirt pocket. And at little times during the day, I&amp;#39;ll pull it out and read it for my soul. For my soul! I don&amp;#39;t memorize verses that don&amp;#39;t help my soul. I&amp;#39;m into fighting the fight of faith. I want to memorize Scripture so that I can defeat the devil at 3 o&amp;#39;clock in the afternoon, that&amp;#39;s why!


	I (Jeremy) hope this is beneficial for you.&amp;nbsp; Additionally, I have also found it helpful to memorize with a partner. That way you&amp;#39;ve got some accountability and an audience. A spouse, a friend, a co-worker - commit to one another and to memorization. I&amp;#39;m glad to be walking this path with you guys.]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>Why Memorize Scripture?</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7532</link>
<description> <![CDATA[
	Memorizing Scripture isn&amp;#39;t just for Sunday School. It&amp;#39;s for life.


	As we study the New Testament in our Dangerous Words series, we are challenging those who call The Journey home to engage with God by storing his Word in our hearts, which helps keep us from sin (Psalm 119:11). We begin our memorization this week with John 3:16-17.

	To help us more clearly see the value of Scripture memorization I&amp;#39;m enlisting the help of a spiritual mentor of mine and several other Journey pastors, Dr. John Piper.&amp;nbsp; Below is an excerpt from a larger article from Dr. Piper, outlining six excellent benefits to memorizing Scripture.

	1. Conformity to Christ

	Paul wrote that &amp;ldquo;we all, . . . beholding the glory of the Lord, are being transformed into the same image from one degree of glory to another&amp;rdquo; (2 Corinthians 3:18)) If we would be changed into Christ likeness we must steadily see him. This happens in the word. &amp;ldquo;The Lord revealed himself to Samuel at Shiloh by the word of the Lord&amp;rdquo; (1 Samuel 3:21). Bible memorization has the effect of making our gaze on Jesus steadier and clearer.

	2. Daily Triumph over Sin

	&amp;ldquo;How can a young man keep his way pure? By guarding it according to your word. . . . I have stored up your word in my heart, that I might not sin against you&amp;rdquo; (Psalm 119:9, 11). Paul said that we must &amp;ldquo;by the Spirit . . . put to death the [sinful] deeds of the body&amp;rdquo; (Romans 8:13). The one piece of armor used to kill is the &amp;ldquo;sword of the Spirit&amp;rdquo; which is the word of God (Ephesians 6:17). As sin lures the body into sinful action, we call to mind a Christ-revealing word of Scripture and slay the temptation with the superior worth and beauty of Christ over what sin offers.

	3. Daily Triumph over Satan

	When Jesus was tempted by Satan in the wilderness he recited Scripture from memory and put Satan to flight (Matthew 4:1-11).

	4. Comfort and Counsel for People You Love

	The times when people need you to give them comfort and counsel do not always coincide with the times you have your Bible handy. Not only that, the very word of God spoken spontaneously from your heart has unusual power. Proverbs 25:11 says, &amp;ldquo;A word fitly spoken is like apples of gold in a setting of silver.&amp;rdquo; That is a beautiful way of saying, When the heart full of God&amp;rsquo;s love can draw on the mind full of God&amp;rsquo;s word, timely blessings flow from the mouth.

	5. Communicating the Gospel to Unbelievers

	Opportunities to share the gospel come when we do not have the Bible in hand. Actual verses of the Bible have their own penetrating power. And when they come from our heart, as well as from the Book, the witness is given that they are precious enough to learn. We should all be able to sum up the gospel under four main headings (1) God&amp;rsquo;s holiness/law/glory; 2) man&amp;rsquo;s sin/rebellion/disobedience; 3) Christ&amp;rsquo;s death for sinners; 4) the free gift of life by faith. Learn a verse or two relating to each of these, and be ready in season and out of season to share them.

	6. Communion with God in the Enjoyment of His Person and Ways

	The way we commune with (that is, fellowship with) God is by meditating on his attributes and expressing to him our thanks and admiration and love, and seeking his help to live a life that reflects the value of these attributes. Therefore, storing texts in our minds about God helps us relate to him as he really is. For example, imagine being able to call this to mind through the day:

	The Lord is merciful and gracious, slow to anger and abounding in steadfast love. He will not always chide, nor will he keep his anger forever. He does not deal with us according to our sins, nor repay us according to our iniquities. For as high as the heavens are above the earth, so great is his steadfast love toward those who fear him; as far as the east is from the west, so far does he remove our transgressions from us. As a father shows compassion to his children, so the Lord shows compassion to those who fear him. For he knows our frame; he remembers that we are dust. (Psalm 103:8-14)

	Most of us are emotionally crippled&amp;mdash;all of us, really. We do not experience God in the fullness of our emotional potential. How will that change? One way is to memorize the emotional expressions of the Bible and speak them to the Lord and to each other until they become part of who we are. For example, in Psalm 103:1, we say, &amp;ldquo;Bless the Lord, O my soul, and all that is within me, bless his holy name!&amp;rdquo; That is not a natural expression for many people. But if we memorize this and other emotional expressions from the Bible, and say them often, asking the Lord to make the emotion real in our hearts, we can actually grow into that emotion and expression. It will become part of who we are. We will be less emotionally crippled and more able to render proper praise and thanks to God.

	There are other reasons for memorizing Scripture. I hope you find them in the actual practice.]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>Summer Series: Dangerous Words</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7492</link>
<description> <![CDATA[
	The most dangerous words ever written are contained in twenty-seven documents that turned all of history upside down. Over 18 weeks this summer we&amp;#39;ll cover each of them.


	The New Testament speaks to a variety of cultures, in all manner of historical settings, in ways that are inspiring, challenging, mysterious, and provocative. Written by persecuted and oppressed people in the ancient Near East, the book speaks with authority and power to people in every part of the globe.

	In this amazing book we find stories of birth and death, miracles and tragedies, prophetic visions, and even a shipwreck.&amp;nbsp; But the diversity of content is telling one story.&amp;nbsp; The story of Jesus Christ, the grand story of human history.

	The New Testament authors were utterly transformed by their experience with Jesus.&amp;nbsp; With boldness and in faith, these early Christians shared the story of Jesus Christ so that others could be transformed too. Regardless of the cost, which for most of the writers included immense suffering and death, the writers of the New Testament dedicated their lives to tell the story of one life&amp;mdash;Jesus of Nazareth.

	Beginning the weekend of May 8-9, Dangerous Words: Taking the New Testament to Heart provides an opportunity to learn the New Testament&amp;#39;s value, purpose, and impact on our lives, the church, and the world. Danger Words will give you handles for understanding and applying the Bible to help you not only better understand your Bible, but live out the gospel.]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>Do You Sin in Your Anger?</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7483</link>
<description> <![CDATA[
	Let all bitterness and wrath and anger and clamor and slander be put away from you, along with all malice. Be kind to one another, tenderhearted, forgiving one another, as God in Christ forgave you. &amp;mdash;&amp;nbsp;Ephesians 4:31-32


	I held a huge grudge against my dad for most of my life, and it is understandable in some ways. My dad did some pretty horrible things to me and my family when I was a kid. Saying that I had a grudge is actually putting it mildly. I hated him.

	About six years ago, God said &amp;ldquo;enough!&amp;rdquo; In a whole list of ways that are better suited for a separate post (or book), God showed me that I sin in my anger because I sin in my forgiveness &amp;mdash; or my unwillingness to forgive. And more than that, my lack of forgiveness toward others is rooted in a failure to acknowledge the immensity of the forgiveness graciously extended to me in Christ. In a miraculous example of heart transformation, God brought me to a place where I was ready to own up to my sin and forgive my dad for his.

	You may not have &amp;ldquo;dad issues,&amp;rdquo; but if you sin in your anger it is, without exception, connected to what you believe about forgiveness. Either you aren&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;sharing&amp;rdquo; your forgiveness with others, or you aren&amp;rsquo;t embracing the gracious gift of your own forgiveness. And if you aren&amp;rsquo;t doing the latter, you certainly aren&amp;rsquo;t doing the former.

	Paul says the key to defeating anger and all its manifestations (bitterness, wrath, clamor, and slander) is to show kindness, tenderheartedness, and forgiveness toward others. The end goal of bitterness is to see the offending party come to &amp;ldquo;justice.&amp;rdquo; A bitter person longs for retribution and even the harm of the offender.

	Kindness and tenderheartedness, on the other hand, are results of forgiveness. Whereas bitterness holds a death grip on the wrong-ness of another person, kindness and tenderheartedness seek life-giving restoration of the relationship with the offending party. Whereas bitterness comes from a hard heart focused on the perceived failure of the other person, kindness and tenderheartedness come from a heart softened by the gospel and focused on the forgiveness received in Christ (Ephesians 4:32).

	To be clear, forgiveness is not about ignoring the sin of another person. That is avoidance. Forgiveness is actually choosing to absorb the pain, the injustice, and the wrong committed against you, deciding instead not to hold any of that against the perpetrator. It is OK to articulate the pain their sin has caused, or even articulate various relational consequences that result from their sin. But it can&amp;rsquo;t stop at confrontation.

	Forgiveness requires that you choose to absorb the injustice of their sin against you. You forgive their many sins because God, in Christ, has forgiven all of your sins! Thus, forgiveness is always costly. It always hurts. Look what it cost Jesus!

	Defeating sinful anger begins with being humbled by the gospel of grace. Said another way, sinful anger is &amp;ldquo;put away&amp;rdquo; by recalling and living out what you profess to believe: that the perfect kindness of God is displayed in Christ&amp;rsquo;s sacrificial death&amp;mdash;for you&amp;mdash;on the cross.]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>Acts 29 Midwest Regional Quarterly - May 18 - Register Now!</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7481</link>
<description> <![CDATA[
	Join us on May 18 with pastor and author Jim Belcher at the&amp;nbsp;Acts 29&amp;nbsp;Midwest Regional Quarterly!

	Jim Belcher is the founding church planter and lead pastor of Redeemer Presbyterian Church in Newport Beach, CA. He is the cofounder of the Restoring Community Conference:Integrating Social Interaction, Sacred Space and Beauty in the 21st Century, an annual conference for city officials, planners, builders and architects. Jim has also been published in Leadership Journal and re:generation quarterly, and he and his wife and four children live in Costa Mesa, California.

	Session 1: Introduction to Deep Church

	What is the Deep Church? Who is the book written for? Why is a third way needed? These are just some of the questions that will be answered during session 1. Jim will explain the contours of the emerging church, the traditional church push-back, and present a third way that moves beyond the two. To illustrate this third way, this session will highlight deep worship, demonstrating how it moves behind the pitfalls of both emerging and traditional. We will also discuss seven ways to be the deep church now!

	Session 2: Deep Culture

	There may be no other issue that divides Christians like the issue of how we look at the world. On one hand, some Christians accuse others of getting too close to the world and selling out. On the other hand, those who take interaction with the world seriously accuse others of being tribal, irrelevant to the cause of Christ. How do we decide which side is right? What is needed is an understanding of what the Bible says about the world. Is the world bad? Is it good? Are we to flee from it or help transform it? What does it mean to be in the world but not of it? The bottom line is how does Christ relate to culture? These are tough questions but ones that we must answer if we are going to be a faithful witness in the world and avoid the twin errors of tribalism and assimilation.

	Event Details:

	When: &amp;nbsp;Tuesday, May 18

	Time: &amp;nbsp;10 AM &amp;ndash; 2 PM (registration opens at 9 AM)

	Where: &amp;nbsp;The Journey,&amp;nbsp;Tower Grove Campus&amp;nbsp;Sanctuary

	Cost: &amp;nbsp;FREE, including lunch

	Register&amp;nbsp;here

	Sponsorships:

	If you&amp;rsquo;d like information on becoming a sponsor, please e-mail Katie at kwachter@journeyon.net

	Hosted by The Journey &amp;ndash; St. Louis, MO]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>Mercy Quartlery - April 26</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7463</link>
<description> <![CDATA[
	Are you interested in exploring how the church is supposed to address issues like poverty, hunger, homelessness, and other pressing needs in our city? &amp;nbsp;Then bring your brain on Monday, April 26.


	If you, your church, or group is addressing issues such as hunger, school tutoring, homelessness, community building and development, or a church plant wanting to serve civic needs, then you should attend. The next Mercy Quarterly will be held on&amp;nbsp;Monday, April 26, from 10:00 until 1:00 PM at The Journey&amp;rsquo;s Tower Grove Campus, in the sanctuary.&amp;nbsp;Doors open at 9 AM, so come early for a time of networking and good coffee.

	The Mercy Quarterly is free&amp;nbsp;and is sponsored by&amp;nbsp;Mission: St. Louis&amp;nbsp;and the&amp;nbsp;St. Louis Metro Baptist Association. Please register&amp;nbsp;here&amp;nbsp;here so that we can adequately prepare for lunch.

	Leading our discussion is Pastor Michael Jones from the Friendly Temple Missionary Baptist Church in North St. Louis City. Friendly Temple is a gospel-centered church in our city, which you may recall invited Pastor John Piper to speak to their congregation a few years back. God is doing great things through this church, and Pastor Mike&amp;rsquo;s leadership in the community. Go&amp;nbsp;here&amp;nbsp;to find out more about Friendly Temple Missionary Baptist Church and what&amp;rsquo;s happening there.

	Pastor Mike will lead the first session, and we will hold discussion groups based on particular interest areas for the second session.

	You won&amp;rsquo;t want to miss this event!

	The Mercy Quarterly began in the fall of 2009 for purpose is to bring St. Louis area church and civic leaders together four times a year to talk about best practices toward addressing issues related to poverty. The Mercy Quarterly gives these leaders an opportunity to share ideas and network with others who may be dealing with similar matters and contexts.]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>I&#039;m a Prayer Worrier</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7461</link>
<description> <![CDATA[
	I know a lot of people who are Prayer Warriors. I&amp;rsquo;m not really one of them. But I&amp;rsquo;m learning to become a Prayer Worrier.


	I&amp;rsquo;ve been known to worry from time to time. I&amp;rsquo;ll give you a very recent and quite ridiculous example.

	This past Sunday, Pastor Darrin was preaching about how to defeat worry and he asked the congregation to read aloud a passage from Matthew splashed across the screen. I was sitting with Melissa, my wife, in the sanctuary at the Tower Grove Campus, and I looked up at the nearest screen to read along with everyone. I could barely make out the text. &amp;ldquo;This text is too small,&amp;rdquo; I said to myself. But everyone else around me was reading along, which meant they could see the text just fine. A terrible thought gripped me. &amp;ldquo;My eyes are going bad.&amp;rdquo; It didn&amp;rsquo;t stop there.

	I kid you not, within a matter of seconds I was envisioning myself under a surgeon&amp;rsquo;s knife hoping to have some catastrophic eye ailment corrected. From there I saw myself with considerably more gray hair than I currently have, dog shopping for a German Shepherd to help me stumble to my boys&amp;rsquo; T-Ball game I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even be able to see!

	I know what you&amp;rsquo;re thinking. What is wrong with this man?

	What&amp;rsquo;s wrong is I worry. And so do you.

	God did not design people to worry because in perfect relationship with him there is no need to worry. However, when sin entered the world through the rebellion of Adam and Eve, so did worry. When Adam and Eve succumbed to their desire to secure their own future, they actually bowed and worshiped the idol of control.

	I am the same way. I worry when God&amp;rsquo;s provision seems slow or insufficient. From my perspective of the given situation, I surmise that either God is unable or unwilling to meet my needs. From this place of doubt I assert myself and take control, trusting that my life&amp;mdash;at least for a time&amp;mdash;will be better if I am in charge.

	When I doubt that God will work out my circumstances for good, while also knowing that I can&amp;rsquo;t ultimately control my circumstances, I become anxious.

	So how do we dethrone the idol of control and defeat worry? God has actually given us a very effective weapon against worry.

	According to&amp;nbsp;Philippians 4:4-9, worry is defeated when we submit to God&amp;rsquo;s loving control and his promised provision. In&amp;nbsp;Philippians 4:6, Paul tells Christians to &amp;ldquo;not be anxious about anything.&amp;rdquo; In other words, Christians ought not to worry. But Paul isn&amp;rsquo;t na&amp;iuml;ve. He knows that we will worry, so he doesn&amp;rsquo;t just tell us to stop worrying. Rather, he tells us to start something, to become something&amp;mdash;a Prayer Worrier.

	Mounting an attack against worry begins with cultivating a life of prayer.

	Paul goes on to describe three types of prayer: adoration, supplication and thanksgiving. The prayer of adoration is seen in&amp;nbsp;Philippians 4:4: &amp;ldquo;Rejoice in the Lord always!&amp;rdquo; Rejoicing in the Lord is not just an emotional response, it&amp;rsquo;s also a matter of the mind&amp;mdash;a decision to trust God. The prayer of adoration is worship of God with single-focused heart and mind, taking joy in the trustworthiness of God in all situations.

	The prayer of supplication emerges from the prayer of adoration. Once we honor God by acknowledging and trusting his control of our circumstances, it makes perfect sense to take our requests to him.

	Finally, we pray a prayer of thanksgiving, knowing that in every circumstance God will provide what is best for his children.

	When we live a life of prayer, when we rejoice with our hearts (Philippians 4:4), &amp;ldquo;think on these things&amp;rdquo; with our minds (Philippians 4:8), and &amp;ldquo;practice these things&amp;rdquo; with our lives (Philippians 4:9), then we experience the peace of God, which passes all understanding&amp;rdquo; (Philippians 4:7). In other words, when we are not just worriers but Prayer Worriers, our hearts and minds are guarded from worry.]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


<item>
<title>Is There Evidence for the Resurrection of Jesus?</title>
<link>http://journeyon.net/node/7424</link>
<description> <![CDATA[
	Michael Patton has a nice set of posts on the evidence for the resurrection that you should check out. Pastor Darrin will point to Patton&amp;rsquo;s work in his sermons this weekend.


	Under&amp;nbsp;internal evidence&amp;nbsp;(i.e., confirming features within the biblical texts) he cites the following:

	
		Honesty
	
		Irrelevant Details
	
		Harmony
	
		Public Extraordinary Claims
	
		Lack of Motivation for Fabrication


	For the&amp;nbsp;external evidence&amp;nbsp;(i.e., support from outside the biblical texts) he cites the following:

	
		Preservation of the Documents
	
		Archeology
	
		Extra-biblical Attestation
	
		Survival in a Hostil Environment


	Post written by Justin Taylor at&amp;nbsp;TheGospelCoalition.org.

	The original post can be found&amp;nbsp;here.]]> </description>

<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2010 22:27:13 +0000</pubDate>
<dc:creator>Journeyon Administrator</dc:creator>
<guid isPermaLink="false">7589 at http://localhost/Journeyon.net-4.0</guid>
</item>


</channel>
</rss>